<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Techarge Site</title><link>https://techarge.co.uk/</link><description>Recent content on Techarge Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>info@techarge.co.uk (Ling Li)</managingEditor><webMaster>info@techarge.co.uk (Ling Li)</webMaster><copyright>2021 Techarge. All rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 12:14:56 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techarge.co.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>EMSX</title><link>https://techarge.co.uk/posts/emsx/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 12:14:56 +0100</pubDate><author>info@techarge.co.uk (Ling Li)</author><guid>https://techarge.co.uk/posts/emsx/</guid><description>&lt;p>For our latest client, we are pleased to announce the launch of &lt;a href="https://emsx.vet">https://emsx.vet&lt;/a>. The purpose of this platform is to assist Vet students undertaking their studies in the UK to find work experience placements as part of thier extra murial studies. The site has a comprehensive list of all vet practises in the UK and allows students to search a given location and filter by requirements such as speciality or species.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vet students can create an account on the platform and save a list of their favourite vet practises as well as apply directly to each practise either on mobile or desktop. The site was built and launched in record time (&amp;lt;6m from initial design through to implementation, testing and deployment). We choose a mixed tech stack of Wagtail/Django to allow for easier management of vet practise information mixed with Svelte in the frontend to provide a fast and responsive frontend for users.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Latest in Tech 2021</title><link>https://techarge.co.uk/posts/tech-development/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:12:18 +0100</pubDate><author>info@techarge.co.uk (Ling Li)</author><guid>https://techarge.co.uk/posts/tech-development/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tech-in-2021">Tech in 2021&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://techarge.co.uk/images/laptop.svg" alt="">
At Techarge our ethos is to design, build and deliver quickly. This allows us to show to our clients at an early stage what and how their potential system will look like. Our team employs a range of the state of the art tools, that will help us to be ever more productive and deliver successful projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="uxui-design">UX/UI design&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For prototyping and mocking up, we design our wireframes using Figma. This tool allows our designs to be shared realtime between our clients, designs and tech team. It allows comments to be made and even simple interactive slide-shows of how a product might look can be quickly put together. Figma has a great range of tools which allows the design to be converted quickly into html/css code so we can ensure that the styles, fonts and colours remain consistent between design and build time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="build-time">Build time&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When it comes to putting together the actual code, we like to keep things simple. We have a penchant for using Svelte in the front-end. Whilst the rest of the industry are all talking React, we feel the Svelte code is much lighter which is compiled into a small and faster size.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="deploy-and-testing">Deploy and testing&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For deployment, we are firm believers in CI/CD, that&amp;rsquo;s Continuous Integration/Development. What this means is that we configure multiple environments on a per project basis. Each environment can contain it&amp;rsquo;s own version of code, so as new features are ready, they can be shipped out and ready for our testers/clients to validate and review.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nowadays, using a source code control system is pretty much a must. We&amp;rsquo;re heavy users of github and in particular github-actions allows the auto triggering of jobs as soon as fresh code has been commited into a responsitory. These jobs can include running automated tests and deploying the code into designated environments. It&amp;rsquo;s a one-time investiment to configure a CI/CD pipeline, but once it&amp;rsquo;s done, it&amp;rsquo;s a fantastic time-saver and frees up our developers to build more features faster or allows bugs/issues to be picked up sooner, reducing the risk of any nasty surprises.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>